<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This is Bronx Zoo Audio Tour Guide data version 0.2 last updated 3/24/2021  -->
<guide>
	<bestiary>
		<animal id="1">
			<zooname>Southern Pudu</zooname>
			<pictureurl>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrandtc/UnofficialBronxZooAudioTour/master/images/a1.jpg</pictureurl>
			<commonname id="1">Chilean Pudu</commonname>
			<binomialnomenclature>Pudu puda</binomialnomenclature>
			<family>Cervidae</family>
			<class>Mammalia</class>
			<IUCNConservationStatus>Near Threatened</IUCNConservationStatus>
			<naturallocation>
				Central Chile and along the adjacent Argentine
				border
			</naturallocation>
			<originalcontent>
				<information>
					<paragraph>Southern Pudu are the smallest 
					deer on earth, measuring from 0.6 to 0.825
					meters long. They're found in nature in
					the temperate zone of Southern Chile  
					and in Argentina in the adjacent region. Their
					native climate is on average warmer and wetter
					 than New York, but is still considered
					temporate rather than tropical. Their maximum lifespan in
					captivity is thought to be about 18, and in nature about
					10 years. They eat
					fallen fruit, ferns, vines and small
					tree foliage. These animals get most of liquid from their
					food, and are
					only occasionally seen drinking water.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>Baby Chilean Pudu have white spots on their coat.
					Males have short (less than 10 cm) spike antlers. Pudu
					mate in the fall
					and give birth in the spring (bare in
					mind in Chile the seasons are
					opposite). Usually only one fawn
					is born per year. It takes three
					months for a fawn to
					become full sized, six months for a female to
					reach
					sexual maturity and eighteen months for males.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>Chilean Pudu, being super cute, have been captured
					in the wild for use as
					pets, contributing to their
					declining population. It's speculated that the reason
					they have evolved to be
					so small is to be able to
					more easily slip though the dense
					undergrowth and
					bamboo thinkets in their native environment.</paragraph>
				</information>
			</originalcontent>
			<viewingpoints>
				<viewingpoint id="1">
					<latitude>40.848938</latitude>
					<longitude>-73.879588</longitude>
				</viewingpoint>
			</viewingpoints>
				<readinglist>
					<readmore id="1">
						<type>eol</type>
						<link>https://eol.org/pages/129574</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="2">
						<type>wikipedia</type>
						<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pud%C3%BA</link>
						<comment>The article covers both the southern and north pudu
						</comment>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="3">
						<type>IUCN Red List</type>
						<link>https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/18848/22164089</link>
					</readmore>
				</readinglist>
				<parentstructure>0</parentstructure>
		</animal>
		<animal id="2">
			<zooname>Giraffe</zooname>
			<pictureurl>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrandtc/UnofficialBronxZooAudioTour/master/images/a2.jpg</pictureurl>
			<binomialnomenclature>Giraffa camelopardalis</binomialnomenclature>
			<family>Giraffidae</family>
			<class>Mammalia</class>
			<IUCNConservationStatus>Vulnerable</IUCNConservationStatus>
			<naturallocation>
				Africa, especially towards the south
			</naturallocation>
			<originalcontent>
				<information>
					<paragraph>This is a giraffe, the tallest living terrestrial animal
					which has facinated humanity for millenia. 2016 estimates
					indicate that there are around 100 thousand of
					these animals in the wild, with more than 1500 in zoos.
					Although giraffe are traditionally considered one
					species, research in mitochondrial and nuclear DNA
					reveals that there are actually eight species. Giraffe
					are members of of the Giraffidae family, along with their
					closest living relative, the endangered okapi (which you
					can also find not far from here). Giraffe are found
					in the wild in various pockets, mostly in southern half of
					Africa.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>Giraffes usually inhabit savannahs and woodlands.
					Their food source is leaves, fruits and flowers of
					woody plants, which they can get to easier than any
					of the competition thanks to their long necks. They
					are preyed upon lions, leopards, spotted hyenas and
					African wild dogs (all of which you can see here
					nearby except for African leopards).</paragraph>
					<paragraph>Giraffes live in herds of related females and
					their offspring, or in bachelor herds of unrelated
					males. Giraffes are very social and sometimes
					these herds hang out together. Males establish
					social hierarchies through "necking", where they
					combat using their necks as weapons. Dominant
					males gain access to females, who do all the
					child rearing.</paragraph>
				</information>
			</originalcontent>
			<viewingpoints>
				<viewingpoint id="1">
					<latitude>40.847847</latitude>
					<longitude>-73.880372</longitude>
				</viewingpoint>
			</viewingpoints>
				<readinglist>
					<readmore id="1">
						<type>eol</type>
						<link>https://eol.org/pages/38813</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="2">
						<type>wikipedia</type>
						<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giraffe</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="3">
						<type>IUCN Red List</type>
						<link>https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/9194/136266699</link>
					</readmore>
				</readinglist>
				<parentstructure>0</parentstructure>
		</animal>
		<animal id="3">
			<zooname>Common Ostrich</zooname>
			<pictureurl>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrandtc/UnofficialBronxZooAudioTour/master/images/a3.jpg</pictureurl>
			<commonname id="1">African Ostrich</commonname>
			<binomialnomenclature>Struthio camelus</binomialnomenclature>
			<family>Struthionidae</family>
			<class>Aves</class>
			<IUCNConservationStatus>Least Concern</IUCNConservationStatus>
			<naturallocation>
				Africa, at the southern end and central
			</naturallocation>
			<originalcontent>
				<information>
					<paragraph>Ostriches are unmistakeable: They are Huge 
					(stands 2 m tall), terrestrial bird. Males are black 
					and white, females gray brown. They can weight 90 to 130 kg
					or 200 to 300 pounds, or as much as two adult humans. 
					Their lifespan is up to 40–45 years. </paragraph>
					<paragraph> Ostriches were almost wiped out in the 18th 
					century due to hunting for feathers. By the middle of the 
					19th century, the practice of farming ostriches began to spread. 
					This enabled ostriches to be domesticated and plucked, instead 
					of being hunted and killed. Currently, the demand for ostrich
					 feathers has lessened greatly, and ostriches seem to have a 
					 secure population.</paragraph>
				</information>
			</originalcontent>
			<viewingpoints>
				<viewingpoint id="1">
					<latitude>40.8477944</latitude>
					<longitude>-73.8804833</longitude>
				</viewingpoint>
			</viewingpoints>
				<readinglist>
					<readmore id="1">
						<type>eol</type>
						<link>https://eol.org/pages/45513749</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="2">
						<type>wikipedia</type>
						<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_ostrich</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="3">
						<type>IUCN Red List</type>
						<link>https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/45020636/132189458
						</link>
					</readmore>
				</readinglist>
				<parentstructure>0</parentstructure>
		</animal>
		<animal id="4">
			<zooname>African Wild Dogs</zooname>
			<pictureurl>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrandtc/UnofficialBronxZooAudioTour/master/images/a4.jpg</pictureurl>
			<binomialnomenclature>Lycaon pictus</binomialnomenclature>
			<commonname id="1">African Hunting Dog</commonname>
			<family>Canidae</family>
			<class>Mammalia</class>
			<IUCNConservationStatus>Endangered</IUCNConservationStatus>
			<naturallocation>
				Africa, primarily in the south east and center
			</naturallocation>
			<originalcontent>
				<information>
					<paragraph>It is the largest wild canine in Africa, and
					the only extant member of the genus Lycaon, which is 
					distinguished from Canis by dentition highly specialised 
					for a hypercarnivorous diet, and a lack of dewclaws. It 
					is estimated that about 6,600 adults including 1,400 
					mature individuals live in 39 subpopulations that are
					all threatened by habitat fragmentation, human persecution
					and outbreaks of diseases. As the largest subpopulation 
					probably consists of less than 250 individuals, the 
				    African wild dog is listed as endangered on the 
					IUCN Red List since 1990.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>The African wild dog is a highly social 
					animal, living in packs with separate dominance 
					hierarchies for males and females. Uniquely among 
					social carnivores, the females rather than the males
					disperse from the natal pack once sexually mature. 
					The young are allowed to feed first on carcasses.</paragraph>
				</information>
			</originalcontent>
			<viewingpoints>
				<viewingpoint id="1">
					<latitude>40.847453, </latitude>
					<longitude>-73.880658</longitude>
				</viewingpoint>
			</viewingpoints>
			<readinglist>
					<readmore id="1">
						<type>eol</type>
						<link>https://eol.org/pages/328697</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="2">
						<type>wikipedia</type>
						<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/African_wild_dog</link>
					</readmore>
					<readmore id="3">
						<type>IUCN Red List</type>
						<link>https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/12436/166502262</link>
					</readmore>
			</readinglist>
			<parentstructure>0</parentstructure>
		</animal>
	</bestiary>
	<structures>
		<structure id="1">
			<stucttitle>Fountain of Youth</stucttitle>
			<pictureurl>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrandtc/UnofficialBronxZooAudioTour/master/images/s1.jpg</pictureurl>
			<originalcontent>
				<information>
				<paragraph>Legend has it that in Pompeii, a city in
					ancient Rome preserved by a vulcanic eruption, there was a
					fountain, fed by the waters of Mount Vesuvius. All those
					who drank from it would be gifted with superhuman
					health, wealth and looks. The fountain went dry
					after Mount Vesuvius erupted and the citizens of Pompeii
					lost their superhuman blessings.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>In 1943, Hyman Gould visited and brought a 12 inch lead
					pipe which proportedly once carried the waters of Mount
					Vesuvius, back home to the Bronx as a souvineer. He reached
					out to the Bronx Chamber of Commerce who came up with an
					idea: They were going to build a drinking fountain on
					Fordham road for the citizens of New York with water
					flowing through the same pipe, probably to get people
					to visit the Bronx.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>This is what remains of that idea and the pipe that runs
					through the fountain. You can't drink from it today, but
					that's okay since drinking water from old lead pipes is
					generally frowned upon by modern health experts.
					If you know more about this landmark, have first hand
					information or have primary sources feel free to
					reachout to me at twcookson@gmail.com</paragraph>
				</information>
				<audio></audio>
			</originalcontent>
			<viewingpoints>
				<viewingpoint id="1">
					<latitude>40.853906</latitude>
					<longitude>-73.878149</longitude>
				</viewingpoint>
			</viewingpoints>
					<secondarysource id="1">
						<type>structure</type>
						<sourcetitle>Atlas Obscura: Bronx Zoo 'Fountain of Youth'</sourcetitle>
						<link>https://www.atlasobscura.com/places/bronx-zoo-fountain-of-youth
						</link>
					</secondarysource>
					<primaryresource id="1">
						<type>Newspaper</type>
						<sourcetitle>The Daily Banner,Greencastle, Putnam County, 6 October 1952
						</sourcetitle>
						<link>https://tinyurl.com/y9hfrw3y</link>
					</primaryresource>
		</structure>
		<structure id="2">
			<stucttitle>Dippin Dots</stucttitle>
			<pictureurl>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrandtc/UnofficialBronxZooAudioTour/master/images/s2.jpg</pictureurl>
			<originalcontent>
				<information>
					<paragraph>Dippin' Dots is an ice cream snack invented by Curt
					Jones in 1988, created by flash freezing ice cream mix
					in liquid nitrogen. Dippin' Dots is based in Paducah,
					Kentucky and is sold in 14 different countries. You can't
					buy Dippin Dots in most grocery stories because it
					requires temperature below -40 degrees Fahrenheit, -40
					degrees celsius, to store. Although they're not cheap,
					if you've never had Dippin' Dots before you'll really
					only find them in places like this (theme parks, zoos,
					and aquariums) and they filed for Chapter 11 backruptsy
					protection in 2011, so it's hard to say if they'll be
					around forever.</paragraph>
					<paragraph>Dippin Dot's was invented in Illinois, when Curt
					Jones, who specialized in cryogenics, was trying to
					create more efficient fodder for farm animals in his
					parents garage. Because of the ultra cold freezers
					the company uses for the product, sparked interest when
					vaccines were developed for COVID-19 that required
					storage at -94° F (-70° C). Pharmacists and distributors
					of those vaccines reached out for those freezers.</paragraph>
				</information>
				<audio></audio>
			</originalcontent>
			<viewingpoints>
				<viewingpoint id="1">
					<latitude>40.848181</latitude>
					<longitude>-73.879611</longitude>
				</viewingpoint>
				</viewingpoints>
					<type>structure</type>
					<primaryresource id="1">
						<type>website</type>
						<sourcetitle>Dippin' Dots official FAQ on website</sourcetitle>
						<link>https://www.dippindots.com/about/faq.html</link>
					</primaryresource>
					<secondarysource id="1">
						<sourcetitle>Wikipedia entry for Dippin' Dots'</sourcetitle>
						<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dippin%27_Dots</link>
					</secondarysource>
					https://www.dippindots.com/about/faq.html
		</structure>
	</structures>
</guide>
